## Quality Assurance Engineer

# **Dzmitry Slizhou**

San Mateo, CA tel: 302-344-4691 email: d.slizhou@gmail.com

## **Professional Summary:**

Software Quality Assurance Engineer with 6 years of experience in web and mobile applications, robotic software, including SLAM (mapping and localization), and computer vision. Expertise developing and implementing test plans, scripts, and procedures, including test case automation utilizing Python and Java. Solid understanding and practical experience of system development life cycle (SDLC) principals and experience working with Agile software development methodologies. Able to work under tight deadlines and rapidly changing priorities. Work well independently as well as in a team. Well organized and capable of quickly learning new technical skills.

## **Technical Summary:**

Platforms: Ubuntu 18.04/22.04, Windows 10, MacOS

Programming: Python, Java, HTML, CSS, SQL

Mobile Platforms: iOS, Android OS Robotic: Raspberry Pi, ROS

Database: MySQL 8.0, PostgresSQL

## **Professional Experience:**

### **QA** Engineer

#### Amazon Lab126, Mountain View, CA

June 2021 - Present

Working on Amazon Astro robot mobility component

Own 2 features on all stages of SDLC including creating test planning documentation, test scripts and procedure, test case automation

Added new module "Human" into existing Python testing framework

Created from scratch framework to automate analyzing testing results from pipeline utilizing Selenium with Java Utilize existing framework in creating automation test cases, resulting in reducing offshore QS team testing effort by 3+ hours on every test cycle

Triage issues, analyze logs to assign Jiras to proper components, verify fixed issues

Execute build validation tests on developers requests

Amazon "Catch of the Quarter" winner in Q2 2023

#### **QA** Technician

#### Amazon Lab126 via Latitude36, Mountain View, CA

June 2020 - June 2021

Testing Computer Vision component on Amazon Echo 8 and 10 devices

Execute regression, bug verification, and performance testing includes KPI for CPU usage, memory consumption, latency measurement etc.

Create scripts in Python to speed up the testing process, utilizing Git to push scripts to code review Utilize KATS on Ubuntu 16.04 to run automated tests

Train new members including offshore team located in India

Report the issues in Jira, triage them and track until closed

Participate in sprint planning and bug triage meetings

Utilize ADB for device testing

Tools: JIRA, TestRail, ADB, GIT, Python.

### **Quality Assurance Engineer**

#### Neato Robotics, Newark, CA

#### **August 2018 – June 2020**

Neato Robotics designs autonomous robot vacuums with intelligent laser navigation, smart home and mobile applications support

Performed testing of the software and firmware on Neato Robotic and Vorwerk robots

Performed testing of native Neato and Kobold mobile applications on iOS and Android

Created test plan and supporting documentation for owned features

Extended existing automation framework. Automated manual test cases

Conducted specific product-related tests such as navigation, connectivity, sensors verification, Networking (802.11 ac), functional-regression, including SQLite database testing

Created Python and Shell scripts for logs parsing and analysis. Utilized Git to push the code to review

Conducted localization testing for Neato Mobile app against 22 European and Asian languages

Transitioned test cases from Polarion and MS Excel into X-Ray

Set a testing environment for up to 50 units. Deployed proper generation of firmware and software builds

Used Jira to report issues. Used Microsoft SharePoint to document test data and robot behavior

Utilized Tera Term Terminal to communicate with robot API

Tools: JIRA, Xray, Polarion, ADB, Tera Term, Microsoft SharePoint, LogReplay, MS Excel.

## **Quality Assurance Engineer**

**June 2017 – August 2018** 

Practical Net, Los Altos, CA

Participated in 8 projects. Tested eCommerce Web and Mobile applications with EPS (Electronic Payment System)

Executed manual and automated tests. Extended existing Selenium Webdriver framework

Performed manual test execution (API, Functional, Regression Testing)

Utilized Postman for API testing, Charles Proxy for networking logs

Used SQL and sub languages to query MySQL

Sent status reports to QA manager

Used JIRA as a bug tracking tool

Tools: ADB, JIRA, MS Excel, MySQL, Postman, Charles Proxy

#### **Software QA Tester**

QAUBER, Santa Clara, CA

**December 2015 – May 2017** 

Tested Web/ Mobile application that connect software development companies with professional software testers

Identified and investigated GUI, functional and technical defects. Filed detailed bug reports utilizing JIRA with screen captures, videos, and attached logs using ADB logcat, Charles Proxy. Verified fixed bugs

Used Browsers Developers Tools to debug websites and evaluate HTML, CSS code changes. Performed browser (EI, FF, Chrome, Safari) compatibility testing

Created and managed test cases in TestRail Test Case Management Software

Performed functional, exploratory, UI, regression, sanity, ad-hoc, and smoke testing

Tools: JIRA, TestRail, Skype, Android Studio, ADB, Charles Proxy.

## **Education & Training:**

Certificate: Build Websites from Scratch. Codecademy. 2018

B.E. Automated Systems Engineering. Command Engineering University. Minsk, Belarus, 2003